you know vintage boxes come in all
shapes and sizes and when it comes to
collections at least they can be useful
here to tell us what to look for in an
old box we welcome back antique appraiser
Gary germer great to see you Gary back
I love this this whole series here isun
they're really fun because back in the
day they really made boxes very useful
right this is just mostly European and
mostly you know older ones you don't see
a lot so I love doing the show and tell
but yeah they have all different purposes
I love it let's start with this one
over here this one down here this one is
currently one of my favorite things in
our store um it's a it's Flemish
it dates to about late 1600s
opens up and has these lovely
drawers with little as I can do it
backwards well take my word for it they
pull out they pull out I think that's so
cool and all like that and and to find
one in this kind of condition that's that
old is really a hard thing obviously to
do and how old did you say it was it's
late 16 early 1700s and so um as I like
to say the family got their money's
worth out of that one when they bought
it it's all Kingwood and Ebony that's put
in there and it's and then little
Ivory handles that are on the um on the
drawers themselves so this would be in
a very wealthy person's home they'd put
their jewelry perhaps in it uh little
valuables and stuff like that in the
little boxes that you have you have a
number of the little boxes there they have
these little boxes like this these are
made with uh these are European and
they're made with um out of wood but
also a tortoise shell and then has silver
on it and it's for snuff they used to do
the the the the Chinese people had the
little snuff bottles that they did the
the Europeans would carry their snuff and
you know snort it the idea of sneezing
was very socially accepted back in the
day oh I see how much does something
like one of those cost or if you have one
would it like if you found one in the the
tortoise shell or the T they can range
anywhere from a couple hundred bucks up
to a th000 these here are probably in
the $400 range okay tell me about the
two pieces in front the two pieces in
front are American and they are store
displays the one on the bottom is a box
that has drawers and they would sell um
spools of thread out of it so it's like
coats and Clark uh spools with that thread
C they would come in different sizes
depending but this is a little two drawer
and they're really practical to have
in the home they're neat decorator item
these drawers that you can you know put
whatever in use whatever yeah on top is
a large and it uh tea this would have
been in a store and it was for tea uh
bulk tea so you would buy your tea and
then you would have these boxes
at home that would that would have
um little tea caddies in them oh my
gosh they open you have to see this
look at that and this one's missing
its bowl it would have had a a glass or
ceramic Bowl in there but this has and
you could do your own special blend you
might have oolong on one side and a green
tea on the other and you'd mix it or
whatever you wanted for your own tea
but you would go to the Tea Merchant and
buy your tea and then at the table you
would make up your tea and then then have
the whole tea Serv is that great so
that's what all of these are they all have
different kinds of Linings in them this
has a little tin lining and then this
isn't my favorite one I love this one
it looks like a little dresser but it
opens up and it would have had tea in
it as well what I think is when when it
comes to collecting antiques like something
like this these would be so much fun
for me because I love using something
for a different purpose than it was
intended sure you know and it could
just be in something like this you're
keeping your favorite jewelry as you
mentioned that kind of thing cuz it's
stunning it's just stunning and they're
just works of art every one of them just
a work absolutely just a display or
something like that it's really oh my gosh
gorgeous but I love this all you can you
can still store your teen it you could
you there's no reason you couldn't mix
your own special blend of your own tell
me about this one this is probably you
may have remembered this from your early
years as a gisha isn't that how you
normally started this this is I was famous
back in the day my Geisha ways
this is a Chinese uh uh makeup
for doing your makeup this is the best
this is the best you got your mirror and
you got your little your little um all
the little compartments that You' have
your little makeup and things like that
so you could do your you could still use
that for makeup today if if you had that
that's incredible what would something
like this be worth now it's it's one in
like this one that it's in it's in good
condition it dates to probably the early
to mid 19th century okay about $500 to
$700 about love that so much
that is beautiful yes gorgeous
when you have your hand on here I'll
move all move this tea box out of the way
so you can see it better is a it's
Japanese and it's a calligraphers cabinet
and you would have your brushes and all
your little stuff your waxes for the
seals and so you had all the things you
needed and was all in in contained in
one little box I don't think this was
used much but it no because it's all neat
and clean and if you actually use it it
would be it would have ink all over the
place right but the Japanese the the grain
of wood that these are made from oops
oops here let me drop the drawers on that
yeah um so it's what they call the me
period which is the late 1900s okay we
wanted to see the drawers there you go
out yeah and it looks like that you've
seen the larger tonsu chests that are
like this he had all the same idea that
would be squared in all the drawers and
stuff like that but this would be for
the calligrapher and and as you mentioned
the wood grain is incredible they they're
the masters of taking the most subtle
things and making up the issue it's
stunning stunning stunning okay this one
this is another great piece this is a
traveling desk so what you do is you lift
the top up don't want to hide you sorry
no s right drop the front down and
you've got your file box here for your
papers you can change the day and date
here with little knobs up here your pen
would rest here and of course you got
your ink Wells and then a little drawer
for your stamps or whatever you needed
so you have a whole desk is so great you
sit at the table and pull out your desk
and you got or if you had to travel if
you're a businessman you could take your
whole desk with you wow I love is that
fun it is and it's beautiful that's the
other thing it's just beautiful okay and
these two pieces and these two pieces
at the end here look like little dra
chest of drawers and that's what they are
these were made by cabinet makers they're
about the Revolutionary War period
late 1700
and you would if you had the means you'd
have your furniture made and they'd
make you a miniature actual miniature
cabinet that's built just like the big
ones and again it would sit on top of
your your cabinet for your small precious
things jewelry or or um or ties or
something like that what you put in there oh
I just love Gary these are so wonderful
Decora yeah they are they're wonderful